# Daniel Mejia

## **UX/UI** Designer

danielmejia.me
hello@danielmejia.me

(614) 558-7109

## Summary

With over 10 years of experience, I specialize in transforming complex workflows into intelligent, user-centered digital experiences, making intricate tasks manageable and efficient. I prioritize usability and inclusivity on every screen, empowering expert and novice users to perform essential, high-demand, and data-intensive tasks confidently.

## Professional Experience

Senior UX/UI Designer | JPMorgan Chase, Columbus, OH

Dec 2017 - Aug 2024

- Led design thinking exercises, increasing collaboration between design, product, and engineering, which optimized internal workflows and cross-team alignment
- Promoted the integration of data-driven design across internal products, fostering informed decision-making and aligning design practices across teams.
- Worked closely on UX research and identified opportunities to enhance employee user experience across internal products, resulting in broader adoption of user-centered practices.
- · Spearheaded the adoption of Adobe Analytics and expedited the implementation of the CASTLE framework.
- Mentored designers, created design and team documentation, and guided developers on A11y-compliant interfaces, improving deliverable handoffs.

Designer | McGraw-Hill Education, Columbus, OH

Jan 2017 - Dec 2017

- Developed design patterns that facilitated consistency across print and digital platforms and streamlined the
  production process, enabling five junior designers to handle complex tasks previously reserved for one senior designer.
- Led user testing sessions and gathered user requirements for a pioneering math product that aligned teachers' goals with national educational standards.

UX/UI Designer | DESIGNATION, Chicago, IL

Apr 2016 - Nov 2016

• Delivered strategic design consultations to two Chicago start-ups, offering short-, medium-, and long-term research-based recommendations to generate user value.

#### **Education**

Graphic Design | The Art Institute of Fort Lauderdale, Fort Lauderdale, FL

Associate's Degree Oct 2011

Art History | Universidad de Puerto Rico, Rio Piedras, PR

Bachelor's Degree Jun 2008

Intelligence Analyst (96B) | US Army, Fort Huachuca, AZ

Specialized Training Nov 2004

#### Certifications

Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) for UX Design | MIT May 2024

UX/UI Design Bootcamp | DESIGNATION Nov 2016

#### Skills

#### **UX** Design

User-centered design

Information Architecture

Wireframing

Prototyping

User flows

Strategic thinking

Usability testing

Heuristic evaluation

#### UI

HTML & CSS

JavaScript

Typography

Branding

Design systems

Agile / Scrum

Layout design

Site map

Style guides

Task flow

### Software

Adobe Analytics

Adobe XD

Adobe CC

Survey Monkey

UserTesting

Figma

Sketch

InVision

Axure

Sublime Text

VS Code

axe DevTools

Jira

Confluence

SharePoint